Hello and welcome to the first
video of the beginner course for n8n.
In this course, we will be
covering all of the basics
that you need to know
to get started with n8n.
In this video, we'll be covering
an introduction to automation.
My name is Maxime and I'm a
marketing and data content creator
as well as instructor for Le
Wagon, a French training company.
I've been working with n8n for over four
years now, built over 100 workflows and
trained 500 students at improving
their marketing and data automation.
Today, we're going to be talking
about an introduction to automation.
Why do we need automation?
What is it?
What are the core concepts?
What is a workflow?
As well as some best
practices to help you get started.
n8n First of all, why
do we need automation?
The whole reason we need automation
is to make data driven decisions.
When we take decisions
based on feeling or
intuition, it is subject
to interpretation.
It is subjective.
This makes it difficult to estimate and
justify the return on investment and often
incurs wasted resources, whether
they be budgetary or time related.
However, n8n When we
take a data-driven approach,
this makes it much more
logic-driven and objective.
It'll improve your capacity to report
and increase your visibility on ROI,
as well as requiring fewer resources, human
resources, budgetary, and in terms of time.
Automation is the key
to being data-driven.
When tasks are executed manually,
we have a lot of wasted time, we have
human error from
repeated low-value tasks,
as well as high human
resource requirements.
This leads to low employee
happiness and retention.
No one is happy to be
doing low-value tasks, for
example, copying data from
one spreadsheet to another.
However, when we start to integrate
automation, we gain much more
predictability and data availability,
increased employee efficiency,
because each employee can now focus
their efforts on much higher-value tasks.
This leads to higher ROI and
lower needs for human resources.
So, what is automation?
Let's start with the definition.
Automation is a predictable
set of predetermined
actions that transfers data
from one point to another.
This is a very wordy definition.
Instead of breaking
down all the parameters of
automation, Here we can
see an example of a workflow.
So, we have a form submission.
When the form is submitted, we check what
kind of company is submitting the form.
If we cannot find a
company, we ignore.
If it's a low-value
company, we can add the
person submitting the
form to an email sequence.
If it's a high-value company, we can
add the information to a Google Sheet.
And if it's an ideal
customer, then we can give
this information to an
account manager ASAP.
So, as you can see here, we have a
predictable set of predetermined actions.
Depending on which kind of company
is submitting the form, we have a very
predictable set of actions
that need to be executed.
And we have a data transfer
from one point to another.
The starting point being
the form submission.
And depending on what kind of company
is submitting the form, we're going to be
transferring the data to
either an email tool, a Google
Sheets, or, for example, Slack
to notify the account manager.
As you can imagine, if we do not have a
predictable set of predetermined actions,
and depending on the kind
of company, we weren't able
to say, if it's this kind
of company, we do this.
If it's that kind of
company, we do that.
Then we wouldn't be able to
create an automation because
we would have to have some
kind of human intervention.
Again, if we do not have any data transfer,
then we're not really automating anything.
So the data transfer
explains itself.
I'd like to cover some core
concepts of automation.
There are important to understand
before building your first workflows.
The first thing I'd like
to talk about is a trigger.
A trigger is what
starts an automation.
So from the example that
we looked at earlier, we
can see that the trigger
was the form submission.
When we're going to be drawing out these
automations, we're going to see that the
trigger is not going to have an
entry arrow, only an exit arrow.
There are many
different kinds of triggers.
A trigger can be manual,
so executed manually.
It can be scheduled, so every minute, every
day at 8 A.M., once a month at 4 p .m.
Or it can be linked
to applications.
We can trigger workflow when we receive a
webhook, when a property is updated in the
CRM, or when, for
example, a form is submitted.
Under the form submission block,
you can see an example of an N8n node.
Here the N8n form trigger.
This allows you to trigger
a workflow when a form
is submitted using the
native N8n form trigger.
Then we have filtering.
Filtering is what allows us to allow or
block certain types of data from following
specific paths based
on certain conditions.
So using the example from earlier,
here we can see depending on the kind of
company, whether there is no company,
a low value company, high value company,
or if the company is an
ideal customer, we're going
to be sending that company
down different paths.
Underneath you can
see the filter node in N8n.
The filter node allows you
to, as its name indicates,
filter data based on
predetermined conditions.
So here, for example, we could say if we
had no company, then we wouldn't continue
the workflow because there is
nothing to do if we have no company.
Another important thing to
understand is actions or apps.
Actions allow you to interact
with applications on the web.
This is what you're going to be using
most of the time when building automation.
We can take a
couple of examples.
So with Google Sheets,
you might want to update
rows, create a sheet
or get a spreadsheet.
If you're using Dropbox, you can
upload a file, get a file, create a folder,
move a file from
one folder to another.
If we're using Slack, you can send a
message, get a message, get a user,
get all of the messages
from a specific channel.
If we're using Salesforce, which is a
CRM, we can get a company, get a contact,
create a lead, associate
a lead to a company.
This is going to depend highly on
which kinds of apps you're using.
Every app is going to have a different
set of actions that you can use for it.
So what is a workflow?
We looked at the example earlier with the
form submission, then the different paths
depending on the kind of
company, and then different actions.
Most workflows are going
to follow a similar template.
They're going to
start with a trigger.
So the trigger is what starts
or launches the workflow.
It could be every day at 8am, or when
this happens, or when launched manually.
Then we're going to be either sorting,
filtering, formatting, transforming,
or segmenting the data.
So this could be if this, then that, only
if this, then that, or change this to that.
This is when we're going to be able
to look at all of the filters, filters that
we created earlier, or make modifications
to the data, to then send to the actions,
which are going to be usually
the last parts of your workflow.
Either updating, for example, a Google
Sheet, sending an email, or notifying a
person, let's say,
through a Slack message.
I'd like to quickly cover some
automation best practices.
Before starting any automation, you need
to make sure that you are mapping it out.
So when someone is going to come to
you and ask, I would like to automate this
task, or if you have an idea, I
would like to automate this task.
The first step that you're
going to want to do is map it out.
Correctly mapping out a process before
building it is going to ensure that you
have visibility on one, do you have
an understanding of the task of the
predictable set of actions
that the task represents?
Two, it's going to give you more
visibility on the different tools,
apps, or actions that
are going to be used.
Three, it's going to give you
more visibility on the feasibility.
Nothing is worse than spending half an
hour, an hour, or two hours building an
automation to then realize at the
end that it actually isn't possible.
Mapping out the workflow is also
going to help you estimate the workload.
How long is it going to take
me to automate this task?
And finally, sometimes
mapping out the workflow is going
to show you where you might
need some human intervention.
If the task you want to automate cannot
be mapped out into a predetermined set of
actions, then you might need some
human intervention in that workflow.
In the advanced course,
we'll cover how you can use AI
to sometimes relieve the
need for human intervention.
So how do you map an automation?
The first thing you want
to do is create a flow chart.
And there are many different
ways you can create this flow chart.
You can use Miro,
FigJam, or any other tool.
And what you want to
do is you want to list every
different part of the process
as an individual block.
Then working left to right, you're going
to want to link these different blocks
with arrows, depending
on how they interact.
So if we take the example from earlier, we
start the workflow with a form submission.
So we're going to create a first
block, call it form submission.
Then the next step in
the automation is we need
to filter depending on
which kind of company.
So here we create a block.
What kind of company?
And from that block, we create all of
these different arrows depending on what
kind of company and what
the different options are.
Then we're going to link these,
this question to the final actions.
So adding an email to sequence
or adding the data to a Google
sheet or sending the information
to an account manager.
These maps can be a lot more
complicated than the given example.
And especially for those much
more complicated examples,
it is very much worth
taking the time to map it out.
If while mapping it out, you realize
that something is unclear, then this is
something that you need
to make sure that you
understand before starting
building the workflow.
Because again, it would
be a shame to get to the
end and realize that it
actually isn't feasible.
This was the first video for
the n8n beginner course.
In the next video, we will be covering
webhooks and APIs, two very important
notions that you need to understand
before building your first n8n workflows.
Thank you and see
you in the next video.