Hello and welcome to video number
three of the beginner course of n8n.
In this video we'll be
covering the node in n8n
which is the building block
of all of your workflows.
Let's start off by looking
into what an n8n node is
and the different types and
categories of n8n nodes.
The node is really the
atom of n8n and every
workflow is built by
connecting consecutive nodes.
There are three main
categories of nodes.
Entry points which are going to be
your triggers, functions that allow you to
transform, filter, or format data, and
exit points that are going to be your
apps or applications, as we
mentioned before. If you're not
ready for the n8n workflow,
then this video is for you.
In n8n, you will find them grouped
by type when adding them to the canvas,
triggers, actions in app, data
transformation like filter, flow,
files, and advanced nodes.
Here we have an example
of the Google Sheets node.
When you open n8n, you
start on an empty canvas.
This is where we will be adding
our nodes to build our workflows.
We can click on the add
first step or the plus button
at the top right of our
screen to add the first node.
In this case, because
it is the first node of our
workflow, we are prompted
to add a trigger node.
There are the same triggers that
we mentioned in the first videos.
By clicking the on app
event option, we will see a
list of applications that
can be used to trigger.
For now, we can start
by launching the workflow
manually and therefore
selecting the manually trigger.
For all following nodes,
we will have the list
of different types of
nodes as you can see here.
Instead of scrolling through the list,
you can also start typing the name of the
node or application that you want
to use to access it quickly. In the
other examples already shown, you
can also use the node Senior When
selecting the node, you will
sometimes be prompted to
pick a specific action from
the list of available options.
This is called the operation.
Here, we can see the Google
Sheets node has different
interactions such as append or
update row, and so on. Once the node
is active, the canvas automatically
akes on the desired action,
such as clear shield, create
sheet, delete sheet, etc.
And here from the optimal andappend job,
we will see that the Area is We can click
the play button to execute
the node as well as common
options like duplicating,
renaming, deleting, etc.
Double-clicking the
node will open its settings.
This is where we can set
up the node for execution.
There are two types
of configurations.
The parameters, which are the default
view when double-clicking on a node.
These are going to be specific
to a given node and operation.
For example, selecting which spreadsheet
and sheet we want to read data from when
we select the get rows operation in
Google Sheets, as you can see here.
The gear on the top right gives us
access to advanced settings that are node
independent, like notes, or
visuals, and execution settings.
We will cover these in
the advanced course.
At the top of the parameters
for each app node,
there will be an option
to set your credentials.
This is a very important
concept to understand.
This setting is how we authenticate
to different applications and services,
as mentioned in the
APIs and webhooks video.
They are saved at an instance level to
make sure workflow building is efficient
and can be shared to
specific users or workflows to
ensure security around
the accessibility of apps.
You can prevent specific people from
having access to specific credentials.
To the left and right of the nodes
parameters, we have input and output data.
This makes it easy to understand what data
is being read as the input by the node,
and what is the
associated output data.
Using an example Google Sheet,
we can see three main views.
This is going to be the table view with the
different columns and values associated.
JSON view where we can see
the output data as key value pairs.
This is going to be the
topic of our next video.
And schema view where we
can see all the different keys
from the input and an example
of corresponding values.
Let's jump into Eniden and
see what all of this looks like.
Here we are in Eniden.
And we can see an empty
canvas for our workflow.
Just as we saw in the slides.
Let's run through adding
a Google Sheet reading its
data and looking through
the different views in Eniden.
So here we have a Google
Sheet that contains demo data.
We have a column with first names,
a column with last names, emails,
and company names.
We can also see here that
we have two sheets, one
sheet named data and one
sheet with company info.
In Eniden, we can
click add first step.
And as mentioned in the video,
choose to trigger this workflow manually.
From here, we can either using the
plus button up here, select the next node,
or clicking the plus button
here, we can add a node
that is connected
automatically to this trigger.
Here I can choose action in
app and look for Google Sheets.
But it would be faster if
we just type Google Sheets.
When I click on Google
Sheets, I have access to all
of the different actions
and triggers associated.
In this case, we're going to get a row
in the sheets that one or multiple rows in
the sheet because we want to
read data from the Google Sheet.
Here, we can see that I already
have a credential that is set up.
These are as mentioned
earlier, saved at an instance level.
But let me just
create a new one.
For the example, if I
create a new credential,
I can choose to use
OAuth or a service account.
In this case, OAuth will
allow me to very easily and
quickly connect. And really
quickly connect to Google.
Read data from the sheet.
So here, I'm going
to sign in with Google.
And now I'm signed in.
This means that Eniden has access to all
of the data in my Google Sheets account.
And now I can choose the
resource I want to act upon.
So this is going to be a
sheet within a document.
And the operation is
going to be get rows.
If you decide you want to
to change your operation, you
can also select from a list
of given operations here.
And now I'm going to select which
document and sheet I want to read.
So here I have multiple options, I
can either enter the URL or the ID.
And the easiest here is going to
be obviously to select from the list.
So here I can choose
Eniden demo data.
And then from again,
the list of sheets, I
have the data sheet and
the company info sheet.
So I'm going to select the
data and execute the node.
Here we can see, to the right, we
have all of the information from the
Google Sheet, as well as a column
that contains data on the row number.
All of the information that was in the
sheet is now available here in Eniden.
fields that did not have
values are going to be empty.
This is as we saw earlier,
the table view, which is
going to be very useful
when reading Google Sheets.
We also have the JSON view with each
line corresponding to one JSON here.
Again, we'll cover JSON in our next video,
and the scheme view, as mentioned earlier.
From here, we can also
access the node settings.
As mentioned a little bit earlier, these
are going to be node independent.
So whichever node you are accessing these
settings of these will always be the same.
We have settings that
depend on what the type of...
From here, we can also
access the node settings.
As mentioned earlier, the node
settings are node independent.
So whichever node you are currently editing,
you will have the same node settings.
We have settings that pertain to
the execution and output of the node.
So the node can always output data or
execute once and not the number of times
of from here, we can also
access the node settings.
As mentioned previously, the
node settings are node independent.
And so no matter which
workflow you are editing,
you will have access
to the same settings.
So these settings have to do
with the node execution or output.
So here we can always output
data or decide to only execute once.
And also retry on fail.
This can be very
useful when using apps.
That behind the scenes
actually use API's.
And then we have error settings,
what do we do in case of an error notes,
and if we want to display notes in the
flow, adding a note to explain what the
workflow does helps a lot when
trying to understand workflows.
Here, under the sheets settings,
we have additional options.
So I could decide, for example,
to filter if I want the email to be a
specific value or the first
name to be a specific value.
And we have additional options such
as data location, output formatting,
or how to deal with filter
that has multiple matches.
Many nodes are going to have additional
settings that are available here at the
bottom, additional filters
or options, for example.
Here, we can also see the input data,
which in this case is going to be empty
because we are using the
when clicking test workflow.
But when we're going to be building
our workflows, to the left, we're going to
have our input data in again,
the table JSON or schema
view, and to the right, we're
going to have our output data.
Thank you for listening to
the third video of the NNN
beginner course where we
covered nodes and how to use them.
In the next video, we'll dive deeper
into what kind of data NNN nodes use,
allowing us to understand the input
and output of the nodes, and how this data
flows between different nodes, with
our final goal being to create workflows.
See you in the next video.