Hello and welcome to video number
four of the beginner course of n8n.
In this video, we'll be
covering what kinds of data
nodes use and how the data
is passed from node to node.
This video is going to
be a bit of a longer one.
And we'll cover some
more technical concepts.
But it is very important that
you understand these concepts.
And so that you can build
the best workflows possible.
Let's start by explaining
some core data concepts that
you need to understand to
make the most out of Eniden.
There are two main data structures
that we are going to take a look at today.
The first one is
what we call a JSON.
And the second one is a list.
JSONs are a very common way of storing
data digitally and are written between
braces or curly brackets.
They are made up of key value pairs,
each one being separated by a comma.
Lists are nothing more
than a collection of objects.
And they can be of the same
or different type written between
brackets or square braces,
and also separated by commas.
A JSON can be embedded.
And what we mean by this is, sometimes we
will have a JSON where the value of a key
is equal to another JSON, we can
use this to organize complex data.
In this example, we can use
an embedded JSON to group all
the information about Emily's
location into a location key.
This key contains itself a JSON,
sorry, the value of this key is a JSON
that has two keys with information
on Emily's country and city.
To access the data in a JSON, we
can use the standard dot notation.
Here, daughter JSON Lexus
lets us access the JSON itself.
And by tip typing dot first
For the first underscore name,
we can access the value of
the first underscore name key.
For embedded JSONs, we can
use multiple dot notations in a row.
Here to get the location, we
can write $JSON.location.country.
$JSON.location being itself
a JSON on which we use
the dot notation to get
the value of its key country.
Lists are simply a
collection of objects.
We can have a mix of letters.
And as you can see here, written between
square brackets and separated by commas.
And because JSONs themselves are objects,
we can obviously make a list of JSONs.
Here we have the example JSON
from earlier, separated by a comma,
and then two more JSONs
that form, well, a list of JSONs.
As we can see here, we have the
square brackets at the top, our first JSON,
a comma, our second JSON, a comma, our
third JSON, and then finally our last brace.
There is a very interesting correspondence
between JSONs and tables, where we can
tell that one JSON is
equivalent to one row,
with the keys being the
headers of those rows.
This might remind you a
little bit the JSON and table
view that we saw in the
previous video on edit nodes.
Here, when we have a list of JSONs,
we can see that Emily here first name
Emily last name Johnson, email and her
email fits very well into the row and then
we have an equivalent
table, we have the different
keys that are the different
columns of our table.
So we can imagine that if we have a list
of three JSONs, then we have an equivalent
table with three different rows, each one
with the values of the corresponding row.
In an again, this is
what we call items.
Here in red, we have
an example of an item.
We have the first item
of the list and nodes
use items, plural, as
inputs and as outputs.
These are the only accepted formats
for node inputs and node outputs.
Even should we decide to
return nothing, no information,
we still have to return a
list with an empty JSON.
That would be considered the
empty output for an NADN node.
So now let's look into how
nodes actually use these items
when we're going to be executing
them and building workflows.
Each node executes once
per item in the input data.
So there are some exceptions that we
will be covering in the advanced course.
But in general, you can remember
that each node executes once per item.
For example, here we are using the date
and time node to format different dates.
The node will read each
item, format the date,
and then return it
as an individual item.
This is how we build workflows by
transitioning items through different nodes.
So here, if we look into this
screenshot here, we have a list of items,
each with different dates.
And here as the output,
we have, again, three
items because it was
executed once per item.
And then we have the formatted
date, which is the same associated date,
but in a different format.
In the parameters of
the node, we can access
the additional settings
through the gear icon.
And here we can decide to
execute only once, where a
node will execute only
for the first item of its input.
To better understand how
workflows actually work,
here we have an execution
schema of a very simple way.
The workflow starts when clicking Execute
Workflow, reads data from a Google Sheet,
and then filters the items
depending on specific conditions.
The Execute Workflow node launches and
returns an empty JSON, so no data at all.
And here we can see we
have our empty JSON in a list.
This is returned so that the next node can
execute once, because we have one item.
The Google Sheets node
then executes once, and reads
three items in the Google
Sheet that it's reading from.
And so it returns three items,
JSON1, JSON2, and JSON3.
Each being linked to
the corresponding row.
So we can see it
outputs three items.
The Filter node checks if each item
satisfies a specific filter condition.
Here we can see that only one of the items
does, and so it only outputs one item.
When building workflows,
the whole point is to configure
a node to execute, depending
on what's in the input data.
We can do this by dragging the key
from the table, JSON, or schema view.
This will recreate what
we call an expression.
Expressions will, for each item,
return the associated value to that key.
The NN interface will show you
an example value for each item.
For example, the first item.
So using the same data as
before, in the schema view, we
can drag the first name
key into the filter conditions.
And I can say, I only
want to allow through the
filter if the first name
is equal to something.
For example, Emily.
Here we have the
expression editor.
And we have an
example result for item 1.
So here, JSON dot first name
of item 1 is equal to Emily.
Remember, nodes
execute once per item.
And so as it executes for
each item, the expression
will have the value
associated to that key.
Everything between two braces,
or curly brackets, is an expression.
So we can use expressions
for many different use cases.
We can use item
variables as we saw before.
So dollar, JSON dot first name,
JSON dot last name, or email.
We can also use JavaScript.
So if we want to apply a JavaScript
function or a JavaScript method to,
for example, one of the item's values,
then we can use any of the built-in
JavaScript functions or
methods between the curly braces.
We can also, in expressions,
combine one or multiple expressions.
As well as plain text.
So here we have, using the Slack node,
we have an example where we want to send
for each item the first name, space,
last name, and then between parentheses,
the email, followed by a short message
that will be the same for every person
just signed up to Acme.
Here we have an example of what the
message would look like for the first item.
We can see that if we execute this
node, and we have three input items,
we will get one message that is going
to be different for each item in the input.
Jumping back into NNN, we
can cover how to use these
expressions and look
at it together in the tool.
So here we have the workflow
that we built in our last video.
A manual execution followed by
reading some data in a Google Sheet.
And I'm just going to click Test Workflow
so we have the data already executed.
Here, again, using the plus up here
or the little plus at the end of the node,
we can add a new node.
This time we're going to
use the Edit Fields node
that we'll cover more in
detail in the next video.
But just to show you a little
bit how we can use expressions.
We'll leave the node
configured as it is by default and
just add a new field that
we're going to call Full Name.
So obviously, Full Name is going to
be first name followed by last name.
So I can just drag the first
name, drag the last name.
And if I click Test Step, we're going to
see that each item is going to have now a
full name field with their first
name followed by their last name.
Here in the JSON view,
we'll see it a bit better.
Paul Harris, Paul Harris.
Marcus Bennett, Marcus Bennett.
In the expressions here, as
mentioned in the slides, we can
see an example of what the
result would be for the first item.
So Paul Harris,
what we see here.
And in the expression, we can
also add a little bit of JavaScript.
For example, I could want the
last name to be two uppercase.
So this would make the
first name as is in the input
data and the last name would
be turned into uppercase.
So here, if I execute this, retest this
step, we can see that now we not only have
the full name, but we have the full
name with the last name that is uppercase.
Thanks for listening to the
fourth video of the NADN beginner
course where we covered
the key data concepts of NADN.
In our next video, we'll be using
everything we learned in these videos to
finally start building
our first workflows.
If you are working on a workflow,
and have a hard time understanding why
your inputs and output data are the way
they are, feel free to come back to this
video and make sure you have a thorough
understanding of both items and lists and
JSONs, as these are key
concepts to understand
when building workflows
and using expressions.
See you in the next video.