Hello and welcome to video number
five of the beginner course for n8n.
In this video, we'll be
covering some core workflow
concepts and continue building
our first workflow together.
Let's start off by covering some important
core workflow concepts you'll need to
understand before
building your own workflows.
Here we have the canvas.
So from the canvas, we can
see the main workflow elements.
Up here we have the workflow menu, the name
and tags associated with that workflow.
We have the workflow
activation settings here.
We can also access the
version history and workflow
specific settings up
in the top right corner.
In the middle, obviously, we have
the nodes of the given workflow.
And we have some zoom
settings to the bottom left.
Activating the workflow is what allows
us to push a workflow to production.
And is what actually allows us to
start using the workflow automatically,
will cover work for activation
a little bit later in n8n.
And of course, in the canvas we have the
nodes, which are going to be the big nodes.
And in the이 The main
workflow menu is where you'll
find all the workflows
of your A&N instance.
You'll find information like tags
and owners that you can filter on.
You can also find all workflows of
which you are the creator by clicking my
workflows down here to see
only workflows owned by you.
You can create a workflow
and every time you do,
you are going to be
assigned as the default owner.
From the workflow settings, so to the
top right of the canvas, we can access
everything that has to do with workflow
accessibility, as well as the error
workflow and how workflow
executions are saved.
We'll be covering both error
workflows and saved executions in video.
Number seven.
Let's look at how nodes are connected
and how we actually can create workflows.
Every workflow starts
with a trigger node.
You can recognize them by the fact
that they only have an output branch,
as you can see here.
And they have the orange
lightning icon next to them.
A workflow can have
multiple different triggers.
Multiple of the same
trigger or multiple
different triggers for
more complex use cases.
And the trigger is what
starts the workflow.
Except when testing
the workflow, it must be
activated for the
trigger to actually work.
In the canvas, when we
double click on a node, we
can see the nodes before
and after the given node.
You can use these little icons to navigate
through the workflow as you are building.
Here we have a very simple
example when clicking execute
workflow, Google Sheets, filter,
and then an edit fields node.
And by double clicking the
filter node, we can see to the
left, Google Sheets, and to
the right, the edit filter node.
Another core topic we
need to cover is branching.
So branching is very important
when building complex workflows.
Branches are how we create
different paths or different
sets of actions depending
on different conditions.
Branches is what allows us to create
complex workflows where one workflow is
able to cover a large variety of cases and not only one
single case. We can use them in many different ways.
We can create branches
in two different ways.
The first way is we use a node
that has multiple output options.
In this case, each item will follow
only one of the multiple paths.
So here, for example, we have an if
node and the if node has two outputs,
true and false.
As we can see, we
have three input items.
And only one item
goes through true.
And two items go through false.
So each item only
follows one specific path.
Another way to create
branches is by dragging
two or more output
lines from a single node.
This means every single
item will follow every path
and will be duplicated
out by the number of paths.
We'll see what this
looks like in just a minute.
Nodes with multiple output branches will have
different sets of output items, obviously.
And these can be accessed from
the output data of the given node.
For example, here, the if node has
an output item for items that satisfy the
condition and an output item for
items that don't satisfy the condition.
Let's jump into n8n and
see what all of this looks like.
So here we are back in n8n.
The first thing I'd like to show
you is triggers and activation.
So this workflow that we
started building, that we execute
manually before reading some
information in a Google Sheet.
If we want this workflow to execute,
let's say, every morning at 8am,
we could use the
schedule trigger.
And this would allow us to
set the trigger interval, how
many days between each
trigger and what hour to trigger at.
So in this case, we would like to trigger
every day with every one day as spacing.
And we're going
to trigger it at 8am.
Here you can see we have
multiple triggers on a given workflow.
And here, if I want to
test this step, it is going
to execute even though it
is not 8am on a given day.
However, if I want to, once I'm done
building this workflow, if I wanted to
actually run every day at 8am, I have to
make sure that the workflow is activated.
So when the workflow is activated,
you will get a confirmation message.
Your schedule trigger will now trigger
executions on the schedule you have defined.
And now I could
remove this manual step.
Every time you activate a
workflow, it will automatically save.
So make sure that your
workflow is ready to be
activated before you
actually do turn it on.
So, continuing to
build this workflow.
Let's add a node after
the Google Sheets.
First, let's execute
so we have the data.
Just as a reminder, we
have here a list of contacts
with their first name, last
name, email, and company.
So what we'd like to do
here is, first of all, we'd
like to remove everyone
that doesn't have an email.
Let's say we want to
email all of these people.
If people do not have an email.
Then there's nothing
we can do with them.
So we are going to use
the filter node to filter
out every contact that
does not have an email.
So here in the filter node,
we have our conditions.
And here we want to make sure
that the email is going to be a string,
a sequence of
letters and characters.
And we want to make
sure that it exists.
So by executing this step, we can
see that we went from 10 to 10 items.
In this case, we can
see that even if the
email is empty, we still
have an empty value.
So in this case, the
condition would not be
exists, but rather is not
equal to an empty string.
Here, if we test this step again, we
will see that we go down from 10 items
in the input to eight items that were
kept and two items that were discarded.
Items that had empty emails.
So from here on, we
only have the eight items
that we want to work
with that have emails.
From here, we could think, OK,
maybe we want a different kind of
behavior, depending on if the
person has a professional email
address or a work email address
or a personal email address.
So here we can add an if node.
And in the if node, we
can add some conditions.
So looking at the JSONs,
we see here a Gmail
address, some work emails
and a hotmail address.
So our condition here is going to be we
want the email to not contain gmail.com.
This will allow us to filter
out the Gmail addresses.
And as a second
step, we could filter out.
So here we see
we have a gmail.fr.
And we have a hotmail address.
And we have a gmail.com.
So by simplifying this
condition by removing the dot
com, we could just remove
anything that has at Gmail.
And we can add a condition
when we add a condition.
And so we have two
conditions in our if node.
We have to decide how we
want to combine the conditions.
Here we want to exclude everyone
whose email contains at Gmail.
Or anyone whose email
contains at Hotmail.
So in this case, we're
going to be using the or filter.
So again, we drag
and drop email.
And we want it to not contain Hotmail
or actually at Hotmail would be better.
If we test this step.
So if we test this step, we
can see that none of the items.
Actually went into
the false branch.
And this is because we are creating the
branch of professional email addresses.
And so we actually should
use the and condition.
The professional email addresses
are that they don't contain Gmail.
And that they don't
contain Hotmail.
So here I can test this step.
Here we can see that we
have multiple branches.
So if I were to add a node here.
And then another one here.
And I execute
again this if node.
We're going to see five
items are going up this branch.
And three items are
going down this branch.
If we had...
This allows us to create these
branches where each item of the input.
Is going down only one of
these branches. These paths.
If we were to just drag
another if from the filter node.
And then maybe
just realign things.
So we can see a bit better.
And here I execute
the filter node.
We can see that in this case.
Eight items are going down here.
And eight items are
going down here.
So by dragging multiple outputs.
From the same node.
We duplicate the
items down both paths.
But by creating an if.
Or a set of
conditional branches.
Then we split the items
down the different paths.
Thanks for listening to the fifth
video of the NLN beginner course.
Where we covered some
core workflow concepts.
And created our first
connected nodes.
In the next video.
We'll be covering
some very useful nodes.
When building workflows.
And we'll keep on
building on this workflow.
To make a more complex example.
See you in the next video.