Hey and welcome to video number
six of the beginner course for n8n.
In this video we'll be covering some
useful nodes and we'll keep on building
the workflow that we've been
working on for the past few videos.
So diving right in, let's quickly
cover some super useful nodes.
Just as a reminder, so far we've seen
the Google sheets node, we've seen the if
node, we've seen the
schedule trigger node.
In this video we're going to
be covering some different
nodes that will likely come in
handy when building workflows.
First of all, we have the
edit fields or set node.
The edit field node is useful
for managing data in your items.
This is going to be, for
example, cleaning up the
data that we're currently
using in the workflow.
But it can also be used to add, format,
reduce any data that's in the items.
So that later on in the
workflow we can be working
with data that's going
to be a lot cleaner.
In the edit fields we have
the option to keep only the
fields that we are setting
or to include all the fields.
Another useful node is one
of the sort of function nodes.
In this case, we're going to be talking
about the aggregate node, which is part of
a category that helps
dealing with multiple items.
So this one specifically is used
to aggregate data across all items.
In this example, we see
we have two input items.
Each.
person having their email and we can
aggregate across the email field and take
these two items and turn
them into one single output item
that contains all of the
emails from all the input items.
We also have similar nodes to remove
duplicates to limit the total number of
items or, for example, to break out
one key of an item into multiple items,
which is going to be the opposite
operation of the aggregate node.
Another very useful node this time in
the trigger category is the webhook node.
When this trigger node is added to your
canvas, you will be attributed a URL here
under test URL and production
URL that you can modify if you'd like.
When testing this step, or once the
workflow is activated, it will listen to
either the test URL or the production
URL for incoming webhooks.
Then it will execute the workflow with
the received data from the webhook as the
initial data so you can automate
from that webhook reception.
Let's jump into N8n and keep
building that workflow we've been
working on and also show you
a quick example with webhooks.
So here we are back in
N8n with the workflow that
we've been slowly building
upon these past few videos.
Let's start off by testing the
workflow so we have all of our data.
The next thing we're going to want
to do is first of all clean the webhook.
Clean up a little bit the
data that we're working with.
We're going to be doing
this with the edit fields node.
This is a very very useful node and I
always recommend that you use the edit
fields node to make sure that you're only
keeping the data that is useful to you.
This will avoid you from
having very complex items
with many fields that
you might not be using.
Anyway you can always
go back to that edit fields
node and add some
extra fields if necessary.
So here in the include in output setting
we're going to choose no input fields
because we're going to map everything
that we need directly as fields here.
So we're going to add a
full name field that as we sort
of saw before is going to
be first name and last name.
And we're going to use
the to uppercase function
to make sure that the
last name is uppercase.
So here if we test this step we will
only have the full name for each item.
As we showed in the last
video we do need the email.
So we're going to drag the
email field and name it email.
And we also need
the company field.
So we're going to drag the
company field and name it company.
Again here if we execute this
step we're only going to have
the information that we need
full name email and company.
From this step we can
all the future nodes should
execute as they were
supposed to previously.
We again have the email key
that's available here and the
email key that is available
that is available and used.
Here.
So what we're going to do is, we
want to read the data from this sheet.
Then we're storing and
making some light formatting to
make sure that we only keep
the keys that are useful to us.
And what we're going to do is we're going
to close off this very simple workflow by
sending some slack messages with
the items that satisfy this condition.
So here from the true branch, we're
going to use the aggregate node.
And here, make sure we
execute the previous field
so we can sort of see
what we're dealing with.
And we're going to
aggregate the email field.
So here, we want to
aggregate individual fields.
And here we want to
input the field name.
So some nodes will
ask you for field names.
And in this case, we're not
going to use the expression.
So here, if you try to drag and drop the
expression, it will automatically give you
the name of the field
and not the expression.
So here, I can test this step.
And we're going to see
we have one output, with
all of the emails that
satisfy this condition.
Here, it might be interesting to
include the information on their company.
So I can also add
another field to aggregate.
And in this case, just
type in the company field.
So here we have all of the
emails and all of the companies.
What we'd like to do from here
is send a slack message with
all of the emails and all of the
companies that have signed up.
So we're going to use the slack
node and the send message action.
I already here have a
slack account connected.
This should already be
set up in your instance.
And here I can write a very simple text
message recap of the signups of the week,
for example.
Make sure we're
using an expression.
And then here I can
add in the list of emails.
And then companies
that signed up this week.
And I can add the
list of companies.
Here, if I test this step, oops, I need to
decide who I'm sending the message to.
So a user, and I can just type
in my name right here, Maxim.
So we're using my slack credentials that
I've already set up, sending a message to
a user, which is myself, with a recap of
all of the signups, which is a list of the
emails, and a recap of all of the
companies, which is a list of companies.
If I test this step, I
get a slack notification.
And here we get the response from
slack, saying, okay, the message was sent.
Here is the message,
and I can see that recap
of signups this week,
I have all the emails.
Companies that signed up this
week, I have all the companies.
Another way of doing this, and because of
the way n8n executes each node once per
item, we could have decided
to not aggregate the data.
So here if I delete this node,
it'll just reconnect these two.
And here, I could change
the message and say, new
signup from email, comma,
company, name, colon, company.
And what this will do, as we saw in
the previous slides, instead of having only
one message with all the emails and all
the companies, here we have five messages.
So one message, new
signup, Marcus at Quantum.
Then we have the next message,
new signup, Sophia from Horizon, etc.
So because here we only have a few people
in our items, it doesn't really matter if
we send just one message as a recap,
or one individual message per person.
However, if we were to deal with tens
or hundreds of emails, we would always
prioritize aggregating the data and
sending it as one recap message.
Now let's take a quick look at
a webhook workflow example.
So here I'm going to add to
my canvas a webhook trigger.
This will give me a test
URL and a production URL.
The test URL will be used when testing the
workflow, and the production URL will be
used once the workflow is activated
or has been pushed to production.
So here we're going to use the POST method,
and I'm going to copy this test URL.
From here I can listen for the test event,
and behind the scenes I have a little.
script that is going to allow
me to send a little test event.
So here we can see
I used a little Python
script to send the body
to the webhook trigger.
And here we have the usual headers,
parameters, query, and the body.
The body has information
on a first name, last
name, company, email,
domain, and the event.
So here, now that we've
tested the workflow, I
can start building the
workflow from this data.
Something you might want to do
at this stage is just pin the data.
So if you have to leave and come back,
you can always keep working with this data.
So here if I refresh the workflow, I
still will have access to the pinned data.
And then from here we can
build a pretty simple workflow.
If the event is equal to invited team
member, then we send a Slack message that
says, again, sending to
a user, sending to myself.
And I can send a simple message.
For example, email just
invited a team member.
And then I can test this step.
And then every time a new team member
is invited, I will receive the webhook.
It'll go down true.
And then it'll send
me the Slack message.
If I had a new team member, so here
I might have different kinds of events.
So I might have,
instead of an invited team
member, I might have
an account created event.
So what I'm going to do is unpin the
data and send another test payload.
This time I'm going to send a
payload with an account created event.
So this time not invited team
member, but account created.
And I could create
another branch.
For example, if the
event is equal to account
created, then I want to
send a Slack message.
Very similar to myself with.
a message saying.
email just created an account.
Now I just need to
clean up the connections.
So here I want it here.
It's if it is not the
account created.
Then I check if it's the
team member invited.
And here I have a very
simple workflow that
will let me know depending
on the kind of event.
We could obviously switch
out the if nodes for switches.
But that's for next time.
Thanks for listening to this sixth video of
the n8n beginner course where we kept
on building that first
workflow and had our
first little play around
with the webhook node.
Something that's interesting
to note here is more
than just filtering or
creating different branches.
We dealt with multiple items.
And that's going to be
something that's going
to be very useful when
building your workflows.
If we need to aggregate some
average data across a set of items.
In the next video, we'll be covering how
n8n stores past executions of workflows.
And how we can use
that to better handle errors.
So see you in the next video.