Hello and welcome to video number
seven of the beginner course for n8n.
In this video we'll be covering how past
executions are stored for your workflows
and specifically how to handle workflow
errors, which is a very important skill.
Let's start a little bit by talking about
how executions are stored in n8n.
So for now, most of
the executions that we've
been working with have
been manual executions.
In these past videos, we've been
clicking on execute workflow or test step.
But as mentioned previously, when we
activate a workflow, we're going to be
turning on the automation and so the
workflow is going to execute behind the
scenes without us necessarily
seeing the execution of the workflow.
We can access the history of all of our
workflows executions in what we call the
execution log, which you can
access by clicking on all executions.
By default, successful and
failed production executions,
so when workflows are
activated, those are saved.
And manual executions
are not saved.
However, on a per workflow basis, you can
activate the logging of manual executions.
You can sort the
execution log by workflow
status, date ranges,
or even execution data.
We'll cover how to store execution
data in the logs in the advanced course.
For the execution log, you can
access the individual execution histories.
So here you can see an
example of an execution history.
We can see the schedule
trigger that activated.
We read the data in the
sheets and depending on if the
email existed or not, we
messaged sales or marketing.
These are static because they are past
executions and so they cannot be changed.
This is really a snapshot
of the final state
of all of the nodes from
that given execution.
This is very useful when debugging,
fixing, or inspecting workflows.
You can look through past executions
to understand how the workflow works.
You can open each node by double clicking
on it to see what the input and output
data was as well as
all of the node settings.
And if the node has an
error, you will also get the
details about that error from
double clicking on the node.
So as we mentioned earlier,
sometimes executions can fail.
You're going to activate a
workflow or push it to production.
And sometimes, your settings
aren't going to be optimal
or your input data is going
to be in the wrong format.
And this is going to
cause your workflow to fail.
So there can be multiple
reasons that workflows fail.
And it's important to
understand what kinds of
errors there are and
especially how to fix them.
The first method of
handling errors, and this is a
very important one, is
to use the error workflow.
This workflow is a workflow that is
executed as soon as a node has an error.
And this workflow allows you to
report on any workflows that have errors.
Pretty much informing
you when your workflow
needs to be debugged
or fixed because it failed.
This workflow needs to be
configured for every new workflow.
So if you're building workflows,
make sure to set your error workflow.
You can have one or multiple
error workflows in your N8N instance.
Here we have an example.
This workflow is
launched every day at 8am.
It reads contacts in a Google Sheets and
updates the CRM, in this case Salesforce,
with those contacts.
The email field is
mandatory in Salesforce.
So it will cause an error
when trying to create
a contact for items that
do not have an email.
This triggers the error workflow with
information on the node that had an error,
in this case the
Salesforce node.
So here of the 10 items that we read in
the sheet, some of them didn't have an
email and this caused the
Salesforce node to have an error.
Another way to trigger the error
workflow is with the stop and error node.
This node will raise an error
message every time that it is triggered,
every time that it is executed.
And you can configure
that specific error message.
Once triggered, you
have multiple options.
By default, the whole workflow will be
stopped and its status, will be set to failed.
However, we'll look at this.
In Enid N you can choose the
behavior of the stop and error node.
You can use this to manage edge cases
in your workflows by raising errors when
certain conditions are
met that should not be met.
This workflow raises an error when the
email data from the webhook is not valid.
So here we check, If the webhook
contains a valid email, and if not valid,
we stop and error.
The error workflow is
created using the error
trigger node that we'll
take a look at in a second.
This node will output any and all
information related to the workflow.
So it will contain the name and workflow
ID, the execution ID, as well as the links
to find that specific
execution that has an error, as
well as information about
the node that had an error.
So either a specific node
or the stop and error node.
We always recommend having a place,
usually a channel, this can be Slack,
WhatsApp, Teams, or any communication
tool, where you can report on errors.
So people in your team with NNN access
can see that the workflow had an error and
quickly jump in to debug
and fix the workflow.
So here you have an example error
workflow, an error trigger that sends a
Slack message, an email or a telegram,
you probably don't need all three.
But you probably need somewhere where
you can report on errors in your work.
so let's go back.
so let's go back to any button's
Open Actions, let's go back to.
So in this example, we're just going to
build a very simple error workflow with a
Slack message containing
information about the error so
that someone can go and
quickly take care of it and debug.
So here we have our error
trigger in our test event.
I can just come in here
and, as usual, add a Slack
node to send a message
to myself, user Maxim.
And here, just to test,
we're going to say an error.
And then we're going to
include some information.
So workflow, comma...
sorry, colon, the name.
We're also going to include
the execution URL here.
And then we're going to
include the error message.
Error message.
This way, every time that we have an
error and the error workflow is executed,
we instantly know which
workflow has an error.
Then we have a very quick link
to access the specific execution.
So we can go into N8n
and see what the error was.
And we also have an error message so we
can better understand what that issue was.
So here I can test the
step, receive the message.
And once we've tested, I
can change and here not
send to a user, but
send instead to a channel.
And here I have
a N8n errors and.
N8n errors channel.
Again, I can test that step.
And every time from now on, one of
my workflows has an error and the error
workflow is cold, I will get
that message in N8n errors
channel with the information
about that execution.
In the advanced course, we'll cover a
bit more of a complex error workflow,
specifically with tagging
people, tagging the owners.
So we can get the right people to
take a look at the error execution.
Now jumping into the workflow from the
previous video, just cleaned up a little bit.
Instead of having those two ifs, I put a
switch in place and I renamed the nodes.
So it's a little bit clearer.
Again, we have our
webhook input data with the
event type and information
about the contact.
And depending on if the event is equal to
account created or team member invited,
we're going to be
sending different messages.
Here we might want to
handle some potential errors.
So there are two main potential
errors that I could imagine.
First, we're
looking at the email.
And second of all, we're checking
what kind of event we're handling.
So there are two kinds of error
handling methods we could use here.
The first one is to
check if the email is valid.
So here we could do a
pretty basic check and
say, does the email
contain an at symbol?
That could be the maybe simplest
way of making sure we have a valid email.
More complex ways could
be to use reg x's to make sure
that the email matches a
very specific email format.
For now, let's just check if
the email contains an at symbol.
So for example, this
would be email valid.
If the email is valid, we can
just continue the workflow.
And if the email is not valid,
then we can add a stop and error.
And here we can throw
an error message or an
error object simply
mentioning invalid email.
Then here we have a
switch on the event type.
We could also imagine that
we might not have a valid event.
So here in the switch, I
could add a new crowding rule.
And this could be if
the event does not exist.
Or as we saw earlier,
if the event as an
expression obviously is
equal to an empty string.
And both of these outputs, we
could then drag to a stop and error.
And this time, instead of having
invalid email, we could say invalid event.
Now we know that when this workflow
activates, it'll handle both the case of
an invalid email and the
case of an invalid event.
So if we do have any errors in our webhook,
system that will trigger error workflows.
And then we can go in and check.
Why did we not have an email?
Or why did we have
an invalid event?
One more thing to mention here
in the stop and error workflows.
If we head over to the
settings, we're going to be
able to select what kind of
behavior we want on error.
As mentioned in the slides by
default, this will stop the workflow.
But if you are handling with an edge case,
that doesn't prevent the workflow from
continuing, you might want to continue
or continue using an error output.
So this can be configured
on a node per node basis, both
for stop and error workflows,
as well as just usual nodes.
Thanks for listening to the seventh video
of the NLN beginner course, where we
looked into execution histories, error
handling and a very basic error workflow.
In the next video, we'll be
covering how to debug a workflow
to avoid it from having errors
again, as well as retrying.
See you in the next video.