Welcome to video number eight and our
final video of the beginner course for n8n.
In this video, we'll be covering
how to debug workflows.
So in the previous video, we talked about
error handling, how sometimes workflows,
when they are pushed to production, when
they are activated, can encounter errors.
And debugging is the
process of fixing those errors
and making sure that
they don't happen again.
So let's start by talking
a little bit about what
debugging is and why it's
an important skill to master.
So when workflows or rather
when specific nodes within
a workflow fail, it can be
for many different reasons.
They can be configured wrong.
The underlying service
can be unavailable.
For example, if you are using Google
Sheets or Slack, you might get a 500
error, meaning that the service is
simply unavailable at the moment.
Or problems can be
related to input data.
So let's say you're
receiving a webhook.
The webhook can be
missing information, causing
the workflow or one of
the specific nodes to fail.
By default, this stops
the workflow from finishing
its execution and it
sets its status to failed.
From the execution history or execution
log, we can find the list of all of the
workflow executions that
failed and then debug them
one by one to make sure
the errors don't happen again.
It is important to note that sometimes
a workflow can fail from an automation
standpoint without necessarily being
tagged as failed in the sense that if you
are trying to automate a certain task but
no node had an error, then sometimes the
task will not be automated and the
workflow won't be tagged as an error.
So this is why error handling
is extremely important
to make sure that your
workflows execute correctly.
And we'll be covering an
example of this in just a minute.
The easiest way to debug
your workflow is to use the What
we propose is by using the
debug in editor feature in NNN.
This is a super powerful
feature that lets you pin data from
an execution history into the
current canvas of the workflow.
What this does is it effectively copies
over whatever data was in or whatever
items were in the failed execution and
pins them into your current workflow's
editor so that then you
can use this data to debug.
The same way that when
we used the pin feature in the
webhook node a few videos
ago, this is the same thing.
It allows you to pin error
data to your workflow canvas.
Pinned data will have a blue or
purple symbol in the bottom right corner.
And workflows can only have
one set of pinned data at a time.
So you have to work through different
types of bugs one by one, making sure that
you are fixing them all and that by repairing
some you aren't creating other bugs.
Once the error is fixed, or
handled, we can use the retry
feature to trigger again
all of the failed executions.
This is a super useful feature
because when a workflow fails,
we might have 5 or 10
executions that were unsuccessful.
And from the execution log, you can decide
whether you want to retry with currently
saved workflow, or with the original
workflow from the time of execution.
The retry is executed
from the node with an error.
This means that if the error in your
workflow comes from a wrongly configured
node previous to the one with an error,
you will have to use the copy to editor
node to re-execute these, because it
only executes from the errored node.
Another useful feature when
debugging is the edit output feature.
The edit output feature lets you manually
edit the output for a specific node,
while it can come in handy when testing
or debugging workflows, specifically if
you're using webhooks
and you don't want to have
to send many different
kinds of tests events.
Without requiring you to execute
all of the past nodes, and do all your
transformations on the
data, it should be used
sparingly as it is not a
very scalable method.
However, in cases where
retrying is not possible, it
can be a quick way to fix a
backlog of a few executions.
Another very, very useful feature when
debugging is the workflow version history.
When making updates to workflows,
error handling, or debugging, sometimes it
happens we make mistakes, and we
can lose sight of where we started from.
Luckily, we have the
workflow version history.
From here, you can
see all of the previous
versions of a given
workflow that were saved.
This can be useful if you need to revert
some changes that were made to a workflow,
that might be causing
bugs, or to inspect the
structure of a previous
version of the workflow.
This can be combined nicely with the
retry feature if you need to revert to a
previous version,
and then retry multiple
executions with the
currently saved version.
Let's jump into n8n and do two different
examples of debugging a workflow.
So here we are in n8n, and we have
this workflow that we're going to debug.
The first step of debugging any workflow
is, well, first of all, understanding what
the workflow is supposed to
do when it executes properly.
So here we can see we have our execution
logs, we have a successful execution,
a failed execution.
But let's first look at
the successful execution
to sort of figure out
what the workflow does.
So here we can see
we receive a webhook.
In the webhook, we have an
ID key with a specific identifier.
Then we get the user.
So this is another function
of the Google Sheets.
We're going to be getting rows, but
specifically filtering on the ID column.
And we're going to be looking pretty
much for the row with the specific ID.
This returns all of the
row information, all of the
information from the
different columns in the sheet.
So we get email, first name,
last name, and company, as
well as the ID that was the
same one as we filtered on.
And then we send a Slack
message with info for the
specific email, their first
name, last name, and company.
Now we can look into
the failed execution.
Here we can see quickly
by looking, we have an error.
Error cannot read properties
of undefined reading to string.
So clearly here, it tried
to read the body .id.
And in the webhook, we can see
that this webhook did not have an ID.
So what we're going
to do is we're going to
click Debug in Editor
to copy the data over.
And we're going to deal
with the different cases.
So first of all, we
could say, we could add
an if and make sure
that we have a valid ID.
So here, we want the
json.body.id this time to be, to exist.
And if this is the case,
then we can go up this
path and get the user and
send the Slack message.
Here, there are multiple ways
we could continue debugging this.
Either we could say,
if we don't have an ID.
So here, let me rename ID.
If we don't have an ID, we could, for
example, send a Slack message saying,
webhook received
did not have ID.
And that way we
can look into it.
But we could also be a bit
smarter here and see the goal of
this workflow is to look up a
user in the specific database.
And here it's with the ID.
But we also saw by
looking at the past
execution that in the
database we have an email.
So instead of looking up the ID, if
we don't have an ID, but we have an
email, we could try
looking up using the email.
So going back to the editor,
we have the case with a valid ID.
Then we could say we have
the case where we have an email.
And this would be
json.body.email exists.
And then all we would have
to do is do the same actions.
Instead of looking up the ID,
we would be looking up the email.
json.body.email.
And then we would send the same Slack message
with the information from the contact.
What we can do from here is then deal
with the case where we have none of them.
This would be a great place to use
the stop and throw error node here.
And the little message
no ID or email.
From here we have
a fixed workflow.
So first of all, we can verify that
with this error data, it still works.
So I can test the workflow.
And as we can see
here, it didn't have an ID.
So it went down
to the email field.
It had a valid email.
So it got the user and
it sent the message.
In this specific case, we wouldn't be able
to retry this workflow because we had to
make the modifications
before this specific node.
Another case I'd like to
cover is this execution.
What we can see here is
we received the webhook.
We tried to read the user
and nothing happened here.
No message was executed.
And this is what I was mentioning earlier
where sometimes a workflow can not fail
but can also not be successful.
And this is a very
good example of this.
So what happened here?
Well, clearly we tried
to look up someone with
an ID that we can see
here in the input data.
But no data was returned.
So something that we can do
here is again, this time it won't
be debug in editor but copy to
editor because it wasn't errored.
And what we can do this time is
now deal with the case, with this case.
So if we test the workflow, we can see
that the updates we made still work with
this execution, except we're still
not getting the output we wanted.
So here, something we
can do is in this get user
sheet, by heading over to
the parameters, we can set...
Sorry, by heading over to the settings,
we can ask it to always output data.
And this means that even if it doesn't
find a contact, here we'll have a here
we'll have the information
of an empty item.
From here, before sending the Slack
message, we can set an additional check.
So here, we could say does
the contact have an email?
So this would be by reading the
information we would have here in Slack.
json.email json.email
If we have an email.
that exists, then we
send the Slack message.
Here, we would have to
do the same modifications.
So, copy this put it here.
We also check.
And if we have a valid
email, we send the message.
In the cases where we don't have a valid
email, and so the lookup was unsuccessful,
we could just drag a
stop and throw error.
Contact not found in database.
And this we can do it this way.
Here, we could sort
of factor this a little bit
better, seeing as all of
these do the same thing.
We could just use a single if and a single
throw error by attaching this one here.
This way, we have debugged the workflow
and whether if we can't find the user,
next time we'll have an
error and someone can hop in
and deal with the case
where we don't have a user.
If this is usual, then we
handle the case differently.
If it's not usual, we can
figure out what's wrong.
Thanks for listening to the eighth and
final video of the NLN beginner course
where we looked into debugging
workflows and fixing failed executions.
In the advanced course, we'll be
covering some much more advanced topics,
advanced workflow building, complex
data flows, more advanced examples,
as well as error
handling and debugging.
Thanks for your attention and for some
of you, see you in the advanced course.