Hello and welcome to video number
nine of the beginner course for n8n.
In this video, we'll be covering
collaboration, workflow sharing,
credentials, and some
other useful tips and tricks.
The first thing I'd like us
to cover is the community.
And this is really
something that makes n8n
stand out from other
automation platforms.
It's a very active and
responsive community.
The community is a great place to find
announcements, information about upcoming
features, or for example,
to request new features.
You can also ask questions about
your workflows or report on bugs.
This is where you'll find
all of the community events.
What's great is the support
usually answers very fast,
preventing any downtime when
it comes to building workflows.
Finally, feature requesting
is a great way to bring more
attention to a feature
that you would like in n8n.
So don't hesitate to head
over there and request
features if there is
something you're looking for.
You can find the community
on community .enedn.io.
Part of what the community
helps build is a library of templates.
So templates cover a
very wide array of common
automation problems that
are being solved with n8n.
Do you want to
build an API endpoint?
Instead of starting from scratch,
start with this template by Jon.
If you want to backup all of your
n8n work flows to a GitHub instance,
same thing you can just
do this with a workflow
that already exists
through these templates.
This will save you a lot of
time when building workflows.
Enidn.io.
It might even save you the whole time
dedicated to building something specific
that you can just find
in the template library.
There are also workflows for building
chatbox, extracting text from PDFs,
as well as many, many more
very interesting use cases.
You can find all of
these and more on nln .io
slash workflows or directly
from the nln interface.
You can sort them by category,
search by name or by node type.
So if you want to build a workflow using
OpenAI, you can just type OpenAI and sort
of see what kind of
templates are already available.
So always remember to check here
before you start building your workflows.
Also, if you build something interesting
or you build something that you think
might be useful to other
people, you can also
submit it as a template
for others to use.
Don't worry.
No credentials are shared when submitting
workflows, so you don't have to worry
about any security issues
when it comes to that.
Now, let's talk about the different kinds
of access and users that are available in
nln when it comes to users,
workflows and credentials.
And let's start off
with user management.
There are three types
or three levels of users.
Owner.
Admin.
And member.
These users will have
different access levels
when it comes to
workflows and credentials.
And this is made to ensure that no one
has unwanted access to specific workflows,
API keys, or access
to any specific tools.
The owner is... there's only
one owner per nln instance,
and they have all of the
rights listed here below.
I won't read
through all of them.
What's important to note is that
even though they have access to all the
workflows and credentials, they won't
be able to read the sensitive information.
So if you get an API key from Slack,
for example, and you create a credential,
the owner will have access to
the credential to share it or revoke
ownership, but will not
be able to extract the...
the API key or app
token from the credential.
So it's access to sharing,
but not access to the
underlying potentially
sensitive information.
Then underneath
owners, we have admins.
Admins are much like owners, except
they don't have access to the nln cloud
dashboard or can't manage anything
when it comes to the owner role.
So modifying or
changing the owner role.
And then the owner is...
Members are just your standard normal
NNN users, and they can manage their own
accounts and workflows, whether it
be tags, assigning workflows, sharing
workflows, or their own
settings such as passwords.
When building workflows, you
will have the option to share or
restrict access to the workflow
to different members of the team.
It is recommended that only the
relevant users have access to the relevant
workflows to avoid unwanted changes being
made or bugs being introduced by people
who might not understand
the workflow at hand.
Workflow sharing is the
method used to share or give
access to workflows between
users of the same NNN instance.
Users can share
workflows that they create.
And instance owners or admins can view
and share all workflows in the instance.
By default, a member that
does not have a workflow shared
with them will not be able
to access that workflow.
So if you are going to be collaborating
with other members on a workflow,
remember to go in and share.
The sharing option can be accessed
at the top right of the workflows canvas.
You have from the main workflow menu,
you can see all of the workflows that you
have access to, as well as a
filter for workflows created by you.
So of which you
have sharing rights.
There are two workflow
roles, creator and editor.
Below you can see the different rights that
creators and editors have on the workflow.
The creator is the user
who created the workflow.
And editors are just other users that
have access to the given workflow.
Workflow sharing allows
editors to use all of the
credentials that are
used in a given workflow.
This includes credentials
that aren't explicitly
shared with them
using credential sharing.
This means if I create a workflow that
has, for example, a slack credential and I
share it to someone
else that I'm working on.
This will also share the slack
credential with that person,
even if they didn't have before
access to that slack credential.
This is simply so the person
that is being shared the workflow
with can jump into the workflow,
make changes, test if needed.
The last topic, and this is an important
one, especially when it comes to security,
is credential sharing.
Credential sharing allows
you to share credentials that
you've created with other users
in the same instance as you.
The other users can then use
the credentials in their workflows,
but they won't be able
to access or edit the
credential details, just
as we mentioned earlier.
This is very important to
ensure security, meaning that no
one can extract the app token
or API key from the credentials.
And use it somewhere else where
they might not be authorized to.
Users can share credentials
that they have created.
And instance owners and users with
the admin role can view and share all
credentials in the instance, again,
without accessing the underlying data.
From the left menu, when
you open a credential, you will
be able to add new users
under the sharing settings.
This is where you
can add new users.
This is where you can invite new users as
well as revoke access should you want to
prevent someone from having
access to a specific credential.
One last topic I'm going to
cover in this video is the n8n API.
Now, this may seem
a little bit funny.
We're using APIs in n8n.
Why does n8n have its own API?
This allows for two
main use cases.
The first one is to use the n8n
node to manage other n8n workflows.
We'll dive deeper into
that in just a second.
And the second use
case is to access, create,
edit n8n workflows
from external programs.
So to use the n8n API,
head over to the settings
and then the n8n API
section in the settings.
And from here, you can
generate a new API key.
This API key is used
to authenticate to the
n8n API as you would
pretty much any other API.
It's a REST API.
And from here, you have endpoints to
retrieve execution logs, delete execution
logs, create, update, delete, as well
as activate or deactivate workflows.
And you can also create and delete
credentials, among many other features.
The second method is by
using the n8n node, which
has pretty much all of the
same features as the API.
The most useful use case for this will
be updating workflows programmatically.
So for example, activating or deactivating
workflows depending on certain conditions.
We could imagine...
that we have a workflow that we
only want to run on working hours.
So let's say 8 A.M.
to 6 P.M.
We could use a supporting workflow
to deactivate the workflow at 6 P.M.
and reactivate it at 8 A.M.
This could also be done
in the workflow itself.
But here we could
do it using the API.
There's also a generate
security audit feature.
Which can come in handy
for getting all of the execution
logs and anything you might
need for a security audit.
Thanks for listening to video
number nine of the beginner course.
Where we covered
workflow sharing, credentials,
and many other
useful tips and tricks.