Hello.
This is Isayangjobs.
I’m quite attached to my subscribers, viewers, and membership members as well.
I’m quite attached to them.
So, without realizing it, I sometimes say things that are a bit presumptuous.
I call it mental care, but I think there are parts where I’m nagging a bit.
The reason is, this blog, you know.
Making money with a blog.
You just write, you know?
It doesn’t require any special skills.
I’ve told you a lot of things, but I always mention in the comments and videos that you just need to write.
It’s the same for me.
I’m not a special person or anything.
You just have to write, and writing just translates into money.
Even if it takes some time, it's simply a job where writing turns into money.
You don't have to deal with people, compare yourself to others, or engage in so-called office politics.
You don't have to manage people, and you get paid.
You just have to write, so why can't you do it?
Why can't our viewers do it?
Why is it like that, our subscribers?
I think about this a lot.
I feel like I think about this every day.
So, instead of telling you about various techniques, I’m constantly thinking about that, and I end up talking about it under the guise of mental care, but I was so
used to it, but I was also able to do these things from a young age with someone’s help.
Especially children, there are things they can’t understand on their own if they don’t learn them.
And there are cases where learning something at a young age can help you for a long time.
I’d like to tell you about one of those things.
What I’m telling you today, is that you will make more money from your blog than your salary, spend freely on things you want, and not live to make money, but rather
live in a way where money doesn't hinder you from doing the things you want to do, the things you feel like you have to do. I hope this becomes that kind of opportunity.
And what is it?
You guys guess it.
You have to manage your condition.
You do.
When you watch my videos or other people's videos on YouTube about how to make money,
or Instagram,
there's Instagram and AI, there's a lot, and while you're watching that, the thought comes to you.
"I think I can do this."
That incredible idea looks very brilliant.
So you go to your desk, pick up your phone, bring your Macbook, and you just have to write.
But this doesn't work.
This.
Getting from here to the desk doesn't work.
You go to your desk, turn on your Macbook, write some text, and log into WordPress, but in that time, you’re holding your phone and doing something else.
Playing games, or looking at Instagram, or watching YouTube Shorts, or WordPress.
Or searching on Google, or searching on Naver.
This doesn't work.
This.
In between, this doesn't work.
Why doesn't it work?
Is it a matter of willpower?
No, it's not.
Everyone,
It’s not that you don’t want to do it, it’s that you are not in the condition to do it right now.
Your physical strength isn't keeping up, and you don’t have the mental capacity.
People look very strong, but if your condition isn’t good, you’re not in a state to do it, so it’s impossible.
You absolutely can’t do it.
So you have to manage your condition.
How do you manage it?
"I'm struggling to make a living."
"I leave early in the morning and come back late at night."
I said I've done a lot of different jobs, but I've also done a lot of on-site work.
Doing what's called “Nogada” (construction work).
I've spent all day lifting formwork, and hoisting it up.
Until I finished unloading the set amount of sand for the day.
“Yarikkiri” they call it.
I did a lot of that.
I've also carried bricks for days.
I've been to old houses and laid down the floor boiler and done plastering.
I’ve done these kinds of jobs.
When I came home, I didn't even have the strength to shower. I’ve actually face-planted onto the keyboard in front of the computer.
And I’d fall asleep without realizing it.
That’s not to say Nogada was the hardest job I had, there were harder ones.
How am I supposed to manage my condition when it's this hard?
That's what you might be thinking.
But, I told you the story of when I was young, didn’t I?
When I was young, a certain great person,
a great man, a historical figure.
One of the things that I heard from that great person was this phrase.
Am I sounding too solemn?
That self-control was necessary, so self-control.
What does that mean?
I’ll tell you simply.
What time is the most fun time of your day?
For me, it's exactly 11 PM.
11 PM.
From 11 PM, my eyes are wide awake, everything is fun, TV is fun, phones are fun, reading books is fun.
Everything is fun.
It’s so much fun.
That's when I get really excited.
So, this is when I excitedly start doing things.
I do the dishes, watch movies, do everything.
What time is it then?
1:30 AM.
When?
Early morning.
Even then, I can’t fall asleep.
Because it’s too much fun.
Okay, that's good.
Do what you want with your free time.
What happens in the morning?
You're definitely tired in the morning.
Like me, because I am the CEO.
I’m tired, right?
I do whatever I want because I am the CEO of my company, but CEOs usually don't come late.
It’s the employees who are late.
But people who go to work are sleepy from the morning.
Just.
By the time you can properly get into work, it will be around noon to get your mind in the right space.
And your physical condition still won’t be back.
In the evening, after working all day, you're like, “Phew, I barely made it through the day”.
You barely made it, so what?
You have to unwind, right?
Have a good dinner, have a beer, watch OTT at home. Then what do you do?
You have to do WordPress, right?
WordPress.
Can you do it?
You can't.
It's not that you don't want to do it, but you don't have any energy left.
You need self-control.
What do you need?
No matter how much fun 11 PM is, you shouldn’t be playing until 1:30 AM.
At that time, you may have the energy and are too excited to feel tired, but if you don’t restrain yourself at this time, you can’t do what you want to do the next morning.
You should play until 11 and go to bed at 12.
Or you can choose not to play and go to bed at 11.
I’m not talking about insomnia here, because that’s not what I'm trying to say.
If you use all of your energy at this most fun and happy time, you won’t have the strength to do WordPress.
There’s one way.
At this time, don't read books, don't watch Shorts, don't do Instagram, when your condition is best, what you should do is, try doing the things that feel the hardest.
What should you do at 11?
At 11?
Do WordPress at this time.
The fun time, in other words, when your condition is best, that’s when you should do WordPress.
So shall we draw a daily schedule?
Like this.
8 o’clock.
12 o'clock.
6 o'clock.
Check the time of the day when your condition is at its best.
Do it once.
Do it comfortably.
You might be going to school, or work, or you might be doing what you want all day, like me.
But you have to find the time when your condition is the best from this list.
You have to write on WordPress at this time, and also write what you are doing at this time.
When your condition is best.
More often than not, you’re doing things that you don’t have to do during your peak condition.
And you're probably trying to do the things you have to do during the times when you're not at your best.
I'm not telling you to live ascetically, or to live a boring life forever, but at first you have to be able to show this level of self-control so that, to a certain extent,
once you're more stable, you can play when your condition is the best, you can get enough sleep when your condition is the best, but if you don't do that, you'll always make money, go to work,
start in the dark, fail, empathize with other people’s stories of failure, and think, "It's not that I’m the only one who’s failed, but that 100 people,
1,000 people, 10,000 people have also failed," and then start WordPress again, and you can stop repeating this cycle.
Everyone, first, check what you’re doing when your condition is best, and when your condition is worst.
If you check, you'll see that you're doing WordPress blogs or other things you need to do when your condition is bad.
And when your condition is good, you're probably having fun.
This is...
I'm not criticizing you, I was like that myself, and then that person told me about “self-control”, what self-control?
He told me once how to restrain myself from having fun when my condition is good, he didn't even say much.
But it was very shocking at that time.
And then, after that, after I started doing the things that felt hardest when my condition was good, my life became very comfortable.
It's not like I did WordPress from a very young age.
What did I do then, for example, let’s say I thought I needed to read a book.
Reading books is very hard.
My eyes get sleepy when I just look at books.
My eyes just close as soon as I look at a book.
There are probably people like that, right?
Why is that?
It's not that the book is not interesting, it's that you're reading a book when you're sleepy and at your worst.
You put it off, and put it off, and put it off, and then think, "I'll read a page or two before I go to bed.”
Then you can sleep like a baby as soon as you look at a book.
You are doing the things that you feel like you have to do at the worst possible time.
Do you exercise?
I exercise a lot.
Even if I don't exercise, I always pay for a year membership.
That’s one of the ways I do things, it’s not that I have the money to pay for it, but at what time do you exercise?
You have to do it at the best time of day to be able to keep doing it without stopping.
It’s not after doing all the things you want to do,
or eating all the things you want to eat, you should exercise and then do those things.
I'm not talking about priority, but rather things you have to do for the first time, things that haven't been established yet, it's hard to do them when your condition is bad.
And one more thing, I mentioned self-control, but in order to do the things you have to do, for example, this you’re watching right now,
is first being released to our membership members, and it will probably be released to general subscribers a month or more later.
It’s August 29th right now.
I'm recording this in the evening right now, at 11:48 PM, which is when I feel the most excited, so what happens on September 10th?
It should come out right away, but on September 10th, the iPhone 16 will be announced.
The iPhone 16, 16 Plus, 16 Pro Max, and 16 Pro are being announced.
This time, AI and new buttons will be added, so sales are expected to be quite high.
If you've found out about this, what you need to do is write fast.
The iPhone 16, 16 is ten days from now, or eleven days from now, isn’t it?
So, during the time that your condition is best, you need to write a blog post about the iPhone 16 Pro Max and Pro.
If you don't know what this is, of course, I might upload a few videos, but if you don’t know, you should be getting the information
for using the iPhone 16 model right now, when your condition is best.
You need to prepare for this.
From now on, you need to focus.
When your condition is best, it’s absolutely about the iPhone 16.
Do you know this right now?
Do you know the show called “I am Solo”?
“I am Solo” is arguably the most talked about show in Korea.
And it will likely be for a very long time.
It airs every Wednesday, and I used to make a bit of money from it a long time ago, do you guys write about it?
There’s so many blog posts online about it.
They go up every week.
It becomes an issue just after Wednesday passes.
Just after Wednesday passes, the search volume explodes from Wednesday evening.
Do you enjoy watching “I am Solo”?
Do you write about it?
I’m not blaming you, but while you’re enjoying watching “I am Solo”, you have to consider what content will become an issue.
After it ends, you are watching it enjoyably by reading other people's blog posts.
If you want to write a blog post on WordPress, you need to have the condition to watch “I am Solo” and the condition to write a blog post.
And after watching “I am Solo,” you should write a blog post on WordPress right away.
It will be past 11 o’clock.
It might be 12 o’clock.
It can't be helped.
This is the season.
What season?
Every Thursday at 00:00, "I'm writing about I am Solo."
Some people even write while watching “I am Solo.”
But you can choose, but anyway, those things,
You watch “I am Solo” and you have to work at 12 AM.
“I have to work."
Instead of this, no matter if it's 12 or 1 o’clock, to write it after you’ve become certain that it will have an effect, you need to be in good condition.
I told you the iPhone 16 is coming out soon.
September 10th, what time?
It comes out at 2 AM.
2 AM, really?
I'll be struggling to pre-order it from Coupang, but Apple events usually happen in the early morning.
They usually start after 2 AM.
But even though I may have published a post ahead of time, that time is when new information comes out.
All the previous publications are rumors.
After the actual information comes out, I write a post, and I also do some video production, so in order to do that, I barely sleep from 2 AM on the day of the announcement.
But if you don't sleep during that time, you get shingles.
It's happened to me a few times.
So, I have to choose.
Because you can’t get shingles, you definitely shouldn’t stay up all night.
But for this, I manage my condition starting two days before.
I avoid stress, and even if it's fun at night, I go to bed early.
I do it from two days before.
Even if I can’t fall asleep, I close my eyes.
I don't tire my eyes out.
I don't tire my body out.
I don't even go to the gym.
Why?
For the sake of my condition that day.
I do that for my condition on September 10th.
If you don't do that, you'll ruin your health.
Or you won’t be able to write a post during those important times.
Why do I go this far?
I told you that there are a few peak seasons throughout the year, right?
It’s not that I’m telling you to live like this all year, but on the days that are peak season, you need to be in good enough shape to write, or else your body won’t be able to, and you won’t be able to write.
You know that saying,
“A sound mind in a sound body.”
“A sound body in a sound mind.”
What does that mean?
You need both.
Both.
You have to have a positive mind.
And you have to manage your condition well.
It’s not good, but if you don't manage your condition, and you think you can do it with your will, it's a bit arrogant.
I have acquaintances who do blogs and things I do, and there's an acquaintance who is really good at it.
It’s astonishing.
I’m always asking them about things.
It's been a while, but when they first started, they met with me for one day, and then after that,
they didn't do anything else, and from the day they ordered their Macbook, they only do this.
What is it?
Digital Nomad.
They only do things related to digital nomad.
They don't do anything else.
You shouldn't overdo it too much, but,
In other words, what does that mean?
They are doing this during the time when their condition is best.
They don’t ruin their condition with other things.
Everyone, you might feel like I spoke a bit randomly, but write down a clock once.
And write down what you’re doing when your condition is best.
When your condition is best, you're probably playing.
When your condition is best, you're probably lying down and watching TV.
So instead of watching TV or lying down, or reading a book,
I'm not saying you shouldn't do it, do these things when your condition isn’t good.
I recommend that you write a post when your condition is good.
Also, if there is an exact timing that you need to write a post, even if your body feels okay, try to manage your condition ahead of time for that time, and then,
like I said at the beginning, the worry I have,
"Why can’t I make money when I write?"
The answer to that worry will definitely be solved.
Okay, I'll stop here for today.
This was Isayangjobs.
See you next time.
Goodbye.