With the emergence of things like Chat GPT and GitHub Copilot, coding with AI has become very common now, right?
On YouTube, they keep saying that AI does all the coding, so why are we learning how to code? They say developers are going to become unnecessary. Even computer science majors
and junior developers come to me and ask, "Are we doing the right thing?"
It's natural to have these concerns.
But within big tech companies, the atmosphere seems a bit different.
How is it different? On YouTube, about 95 out of 100 people express the opinion that "AI does all the coding now,
developers are finished, or there is no need to study coding."
But within big tech, about 20 out of 100 people seem to be actively using coding in their daily lives.
And even that's not so much when we're creating business logic but more for what we call simple labor, like
cleaning up the codebase or adding missing unit tests; that's when they're using AI more. We want to use it in more
places but the usability of AI models decreases as the codebase gets bigger, so it's a bit difficult for now.
I feel there's a bit of a difference between the opinions on YouTube and inside big tech.
But what does that mean? When we're doing side projects, coding for fun on our own, or if we're a member of a smaller team,
then using AI models to code can be a very good way to increase our productivity.
So today, let's review tools that help us code with AI.
Okay, the first tool we'll review is using GitHub Copilot in the coding editor VS Code, which is Visual Studio Code.
I also primarily use VS Code when I code, and I've used, but also not used, GitHub Copilot.
First, let's try to make a user sign-up page together.
Creating a user sign-up page...
But it would be good to try making it without AI first, so let's do that first.
The stack I'm using now is Next.js, React, and Tailwind.css. You don't need to know what these are, it doesn't matter.
Here, if I write "Hello World" on the left, it appears on the right like this; the code appears on the right.
That's all you need to know.
First, let's try coding as much as possible without using AI.
So, to create a sign-up, we need to have "Sign up" at the very top.
You can see that on the right, and then after that
we need an email.
We need an email, then a button below, "Sign Up," and these two should be inside a .
Then, here, let's also add a  tag, "Email," and a placeholder here too.
Okay, so we have a very simple sign-up , but when you see this for the first time, you're probably thinking "What is this?"
Because there's no styling at all. So, if we do some styling, let's add some padding first. Padding...
Let's add some padding.
Then, let's also add some padding here, and then let's also give it a background color.
Background... Is this right?
Bg?
Yeah, that was it.
Then, let's add some padding, and then should we add a password too?
Password... "Password"... We added a password.
I'd like the "Sign Up" text to be a bit bigger.
Yeah, it's a bit bigger now.
Then, let's also add some padding... some padding here.
Okay, this is a very simple sign-up form we made without AI.
If you enter "money@gmail.com", password "12341234" and click "Sign Up", you will be signed up.
But right now, nothing happens when you click this button.
So let's just do this much...
Now, shall we try using some AI? Right?
Let's commit first...
So, here's how to use AI: first, select all this, press command-I, and Copilot will pop up like this.
It says GPT-4 here, and you can also change the model like this.
You can change the model.
Now, it asks what you want to ask Copilot to do.
Then, I'll say "Make this prettier."
Because you can see it's not very pretty right now.
"Make this sign-off form a lot prettier with Tailwind CSS"
You can do it in Korean, but I'm comfortable with English, so I'll do it in English.
Let's see how it changes it.
It's adding some styling.
It's adding a bunch, let's see how it is.
You can click the Accept button, or press command-Enter.
Okay, if you save, you can see a very pretty sign-up form has been created.
One more thing we need to do is that the "Sign Up" button isn't doing anything right now, right?
So, can we add that functionality?
So that when we click "Sign Up," it actually inserts a user record into the database. Right?
Let's ask again.
"When update the code so that when you click..."
"When you submit the form..."
"Actually call an API endpoint."
When the sign-up button is clicked, call an API service and create a user record.
But we don't have an API service now, so assume that there is an API service.
If we do that...
It's adding state.
Added API endpoint... and updated everything below with the code. Right?
We have an error.
Looking at this error message, I see, "Ah, this requires useClient in Next.js."
"It's because there's no useClient."
Looking at it, it's working... So if you enter "hello world..."
when you click this button... this API's handleSubmit function...
You can see that it automatically calls the API.
But one thing that's lacking here.
Usually when you sign up, you type your password twice, right?
We should have one more form input... So let's ask it to fix that.
Here...
I'll ask again.
"This is... This is a sign of form."
"But there is only one password input."
"Add one more password confirmation input."
Add one more input field for password confirmation.
Then it'll automatically add a "Password Confirmation" field.
And if we accept and save it, you can see that password confirmation is also there. Right?
But one more thing that I don't like is that... if I'm already a member, I should go to the login page instead of signing up here...
but there is no link for that. Right?
So, let's ask it to add that too.
Let's ask it to add it.
"Create a link to the login page."
"So that if I'm already a user... then I can click the link... to go to that page."
Login link... We could add it ourselves, but it's annoying...
Then it goes through the code... and goes, "Oh!"
"I can put it here."
It's interesting that it automatically added "Already a member?"
Then...
If you do this...
It wrote the code wrong.
Because...
In Next.js, you can't put an  tag inside a link component but it did it, so... It's not perfect. Not yet.
So, I'll just fix this part separately.
If I fix it separately..."Already a member?"
"Log in."
Okay, so where does this go when I click it?
When I click it, it goes to the login page...
But we don't have a login page. Right?
Then again...
Can we ask Copilot to make a login page for us?
Then...
This time, we're going to...
Instead of chatting with Copilot inside the file...
Let's try using the "edit with copilot" tool.
Okay, then...
Let's put the current sign-up page in the working set.
It says we're adding context to this task.
Then... we have the sign-up page, but we don't have a login page.
The login page...
The path is "app/login/page.tsx"...
Create it following the coding style of the sign-up page.
Let's try that.
Then, if we send the request...
It automatically tries to make something similar to a login page?
So if we go there, you can see it working hard...
It's creating it.
Then we wait until it's all done and...
Accept it...
And if we save, you can see that a login page has been created, and if you click the sign-up link there, you'll see that the sign-up works as well.
It works well.
But one more thing that I don't like here is... what do I do if I lose my password here...
There's no way to do that.
There's no way to find it.
So, here, let's chat with the login page file again...
"add a way to reset password."
I'll do it in Korean.
Add a way to reset the password.
If I do that...
Now...
It goes through the existing lines...
And if you look below, "Ah!"
"We can add the reset here."
So, if we do this and save, you can see that a link to reset the password has also been added.
Like you saw when I was coding earlier, when I do frontend coding, if the codebase isn't big,
then I basically just do the coding very roughly.
Then, I add basic styling or things I missed, for example, like this...
"Password Confirmation" or something like that needs to be added back in,
then I usually use AI like this to try to avoid doing the coding myself as much as possible.
That way, I can write more code in a shorter time. But, like you saw at the beginning...
The code sometimes isn't perfect.
When that happens, I look at the code and fix the bug myself, or use a better model...
and try it again, or tell the AI "This bug popped up, so fix your code yourself."
I try to use AI as much as possible.
Next, we'll look at an editor called Cursor.
Cursor is an editor that is a fork of VSCode.
Here, a "fork" means taking the codebase of an open-source project as is, then adding the features you want to add to it,
and creating a new codebase. That's called forking. So, being a forked codebase of VSCode means
it's very similar, but let's look at what the differences are.
It's a very simple sign-up form.
Let's take this code and ask it to "make it pretty" again.
The method for using it is very similar.
We press Command-K, and this time...
Should we do it in Korean?
"Make the sign-up form I'm looking at much prettier."
Here, the model is GPT-4, but
you can also change the model here.
Let's use the same one for now.
If you look, you can see that it changes it like this, and if you accept, you can see that it made it similarly.
Nicely... The style is a bit different, but it's okay with me. And what did we ask it to do again?
Now, we need to make the sign-up button work properly.
So, when the sign-up button is clicked, call the API service and actually create user information.
However, since we don't have an API service yet...
Just mark it.
If we do that...
Yeah, it's also adding State like before.
It fixed the code...
Now it added the code like this.
Yeah. If I save... there's a bug.
The bug from before is still there, right?
So if we add "useClient", it's fixed, and if you look, there's another bug, it didn't use type.
This is TypeScript but it didn't use type, so add type where it needs it.
Then I'll ask it to do that.
A few types are missing, add type where it's needed.
If I do that...
It automatically adds type and it works fine.
Let's also try asking it to add a password.
Then here, "Add a password confirmation form field."
Yeah. It added a State again and added password confirmation.
Now, if you want to ask something about the code here,
select the code you want to ask about and press Command-L and a chat window will pop up like this.
Okay, so here, what...
"Why are there two fields here?"
If you ask...
The reason to use two password fields in the sign-up form is this.
It will come up like that.
Then, if you select everything and ask, "Should I add a link to the login page?"
It'll say, "Yes, adding a link is a good idea. Please add it."
And things like that. This is a feature in Copilot too, but Cursor also supports it well.
So then, what we did earlier,
"What do I need to do to add a file for the login page?"
It's similar, but if you press Command-I, this thing called Composer will pop up.
This is similar to the "Copilot Edit" tool you saw in GitHub Copilot earlier.
Here, you can just say, "Following the coding style of this sign-up page, create a login page in the 'app/login/page.tsx' path."
If you do that, you can see that I haven't joined the "Cursor Pro" membership.
The reason I haven't joined is that, like you saw earlier, Copilot and Cursor have very similar functions, the UX is almost the same,
and even both support multiple models.
But there's one thing that Cursor does better than Copilot, and that's that if you go to settings and then model, you can use the OpenAI API,
or API keys like an Anthropic API key or another service provider's API key, and only pay for what you've used.
and only pay for what you've used.
So, instead of paying the service provider who provides the Cursor editor, I would pay for my usage of the OpenAI model if I'm going to use it,
and if I'm going to use the Anthropic API model, then I'll only pay for my usage of the Anthropic model.
So, usually, even if you code very actively, it would be hard to use more than 50 cents or so.
But if a monthly membership fee is around $10 or $20, it could be a more economical method,
depending on how much coding you actually do.
If I'm asked, "Which one would you use between these two coding editors?"
I would probably just use Copilot with VS Code.
There are two main reasons. The first reason is reliability.
Microsoft is making VS Code,
and Cursor is forked from VS Code, so I think that Microsoft is going to be a bit better at combining a coding editor and a model,
and there's the issue of reliability of not using my data in a weird way.
And the second reason is that there is no difference in UI UX.
When Cursor came out, there was a big difference in UI UX compared to using Copilot in VS Code.
So people were saying "Wow, Cursor..."
"If you're going to use AI, then Cursor is much better than using Copilot in VS Code."
But VS Code has caught up a lot, and as you can see now, whether you use Copilot in VS Code or AI in Cursor, there isn't really much
difference in convenience, so I think it's better to just use VS Code, because when VS Code
is updated, Cursor might not be able to keep up, since it's a forked version. Right?
So, I think "Ah, it's better to just keep using the editor I usually use."
That's the thought I have.
There are many more AI tools other than Cursor or VS Code, actually.
There are some from Codium, or some that you can use by adding an extension to VS Code, or even by adding a local LLM model, but
the most common one that you can use right now is either Cursor or Copilot.
And if you don't want to pay $10 a month,
and just want to pay for the API for what you use,
then in that case, Cursor can be a good alternative. Got it?
Okay, so today, we took a look at coding using AI together. In the next video, we'll talk more about AI coding.
See you in the next video.